## **Matt Dunn**

Newark, Nottinghamshire I https://www.linkedin.com/in/dunnm

## **Principal Consultant**

Certified Google Professional Cloud Architect with a strong history of application and cloud architecture and development in the e-commerce, logistics, manufacturing and defence sectors. Skilled in a wide range of patterns, languages and frameworks, having recently spent six years in a pivotal role at one of Sheffield's fastest growing software consultancy startups.

## **Key Skills**

#### **Architecture**

- · Cloud (Google Cloud, AWS)
- Docker, Kubernetes, microservices
- HCL Commerce
- · Mobile and IoT
- API driven architecture: REST and OpenAPI

### **Development**

- Java, C++, TypeScript, Python, Unix/Linux
- · JavaScript, Angular
- · HTML, CSS
- Middleware: IBM WebSpher Application Server, Apache Tomcat, IBM MQ, ActiveMQ

#### Other

- Strong presentational and documentation skills
- Training, mentoring and leadership
- Middleware: IBM WebSphere
   Excellent analytical abilities
  - DevOps: Git, GitLab, Jenkins, Terraform

# **Employment**

#### Computacenter plc, Remote / Nottingham / London

Principal Consultant, Multicloud Team, Consultancy Practice August 2021 - Present

As a senior member of Computacenter's multicloud consultancy team, I have assumed the role of application modernisation lead in an ambitious new Google Cloud sub-team. Guiding globally distributed teams of skilled engineers, I have delivered complex projects, and driven presales engagements for several national and global organisations.

#### **Duties, Responsibilities, Skills, and Achievements**

- Consultancy:
  - Delivery of service definitions for Google's GKE and Anthos platforms, including proof of concept and demo development with Terraform and Kubernetes, CI/CD in GitLab, workshop design, and construction of presentational and marketing materials;
  - AWS consultancy to one of the UK's largest retailers, delivering bespoke security analysis solutions with Python;
  - AWS engineering into the financial services sector, including platform development with Terraform, and integration with Snowflake via AWS Lambda.
- · Technical Presales:
  - Presales lead for a major contract to deliver Google Cloud resale and consultancy services into a major healthcare provider.

#### DeeperThanBlue Ltd, Sheffield

Principal Solutions Architect July 2014 - August 2021

## **CSI Ltd, Nottingham**

Solution Developer August 2013 - July 2014

DeeperThanBlue, a dynamic startup which began trading in 2014 as a spin-off from CSI Ltd,

specialise in enterprise-grade software solutions focusing on e-commerce, integration, mobile and analytics.

As one of the initial employees at DeeperThanBlue, I was instrumental in helping the company grow from a headcount of two, to a size of more than 35 employees, across three divisions serving over 25 accounts.

#### **Duties, Responsibilities, Skills, and Achievements**

- · Leadership:
  - Experienced communicator and influencer of senior stakeholders, delivering high quality solutions to problems whilst developing new strategies;
  - Team-building, mentoring, reviews, and agile experience with Scrum and Kanban.
- Architecture E-Commerce:
  - HCL (formerly IBM WebSphere) Commerce cloud architecture (Google Cloud, AWS)
    utilising Docker, Kubernetes and Terraform to provide secure, scalable and repeatable test
    and production environment deployments;
  - BigCommerce cloud architecture (Google Cloud) using serverless patterns such as Cloud Run and App Engine, with SaaS database solutions.
- · Architecture Mobile:
  - Front-end architecture for mobile and tablet with Angular and REST;
  - IoT-type architectures: MQTT, IBM MQ with WebSphere Application Server.
- Development and DevOps Leading and delivering in agile environments:
  - Application architecture and development: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS;
  - DevOps architecture and development: Jenkins, Terraform, GitLab, GitHub.
- Technical Presales:
  - Lead presales architect for several major deals, including the first IBM Commerce on Cloud implementations in Europe.

#### BAE Systems Digital Intelligence (formerly BAE Systems Detica), Guildford

Senior Software Engineer, Electronic Systems Group December 2008 - August 2013

BAE Systems Detica's Electronic Systems Group developed world leading hardware and software solutions primarily for the defence and national security sectors.

#### **Duties, Responsibilities, Skills, and Achievements**

- Architecture and Development Embedded software:
  - Lead full-stack engineer for high-performance software-defined radio solutions for the defence industry with embedded C++, Java, HTML and JavaScript.

#### **Professional Certifications**

Google Professional Cloud Architect, March 2022 Google Professional Cloud Developer, May 2022 HashiCorp Terraform Associate, June 2022

#### **Education**

#### **University of Durham**

Physics, MSci (Hons) (2:2) September 2004 - July 2008

# Wickersley School and Sports College, Rotherham

September 1997 - July 2004

- A levels: Physics (A), Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Design and Technology (B);
- 12 GCSEs (A\* to B), including English, Mathematics and Science.